<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<attractions>
	<attraction>
		<name>Mezquita</name>
		<image>rsz_mezquita</image>
		<latitude>37.8788829</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.779565</longitude>
		<zoom>15</zoom>
		<description>The Mosque-cathedral of Córdoba (Spanish: Mezquita–catedral de Córdoba), also known as the Great Mosque of Córdoba (Spanish: Mezquita de Córdoba), whose ecclesiastical name is the Cathedral of Our Lady of the Assumption (Spanish: Catedral de Nuestra Señora de la Asunción), is the Catholic Christian cathedral of the Diocese of Córdoba dedicated to the Assumption of the Virgin Mary and located in the Spanish region of Andalusia. The structure is regarded as one of the most accomplished monuments of Moorish architecture.

			It originally was a Catholic Christian church built by the Visigoths. When Muslims conquered Spain in 711, the church was first divided into Muslim and Christian halves. This sharing arrangement of the site lasted until 784, when the Christian half was purchased by the Caliph 'Abd al-Rahman I, who then proceeded to demolish the entire structure and build the grand mosque of Cordoba on its ground. After the Reconquista, it was converted to a Roman Catholic church, culminating in the insertion of a Renaissance cathedral nave int the 16th century.

			Since the early 2000s, Spanish Muslims have lobbied the Roman Catholic Church to allow them to pray in the cathedral. This Muslim campaign has been rejected on multiple occasions, both by the church authorities in Spain and by the Vatican.
		</description>
	</attraction>
	<attraction>
		<name>Patios</name>
		<image>patio</image>
		<latitude>37.8751776</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.7851291</longitude>
		<zoom>15</zoom>
		<description>THE COURTYARDS FESTIVAL OF CORDOBA 2015 (patios): From 4th to 17th May

    In the list of Intangible Heritage of Humanity of Unesco since December 2012

    Due to the hot, dry Cordoban climate, the city's inhabitants, - first the Romans and later the Moslems - adapted the typical design of the popular house to their needs, making the home centre around an inner courtyard (patio in Spanish), normally with a fountain in the middle and often a well to collect rainwater. The Moslems made further adjustments, giving the house an entrance from the street which passed through a porch, and filling the courtyard with plants to give the sensation of freshness.

TYPES OF COURTYARDS
     There are clearly two types of courtyard. The first type is in a one-family home in which the rooms are arranged around the courtyard - it usually has arches and either a clay tiled or decorative pebbled floor. The second type is called a neighbours house (casa de vecinos). Here the individual homes look out onto the courtyard - however, these are much less common nowadays. It usually has two floors and the courtyard is made all the more attractive by the long balconies, staircases and baked clay roof tiles. The floors usually have decorative pebbles and there is often a well instead of a fountain, as well as a communal washing room.

WHERE ARE THEY?
     The most characteristic district is the Alcázar Viejo district, between the Alcázar and the parish of San Basilio, although there are also many in the districts of Santa Marina, around the church of San Lorenzo and near la Magdalena. Just around the Mosque-Cathedral, there are also very beautiful old examples of courtyards in the old Jewish quarter. The most beautiful courtyards of all are to be found in the Palacio de Viana (Viana Palace), with twelve different courtyards.

COURTYARDS COMPETITION
    Since 1921, the Town Hall has organised a competition of Courtyards and Crosses in the first week of May, and the owners decorate their houses with great care to try and win the prestigious award offered by the authorities. A festival runs in parallel with a number of performances by the best singers and dancers on the scene, while the local fino wine from Montilla-Moriles flows freely and delicious tapas are served.

    It is thanks to these events that the Cordoban courtyard is becoming more and more important in popular festivities, and helps the general public to celebrate and welcome these festivals with enthusiasm and hospitality.
		</description>
	</attraction>
	<attraction>
		<name>Plaza del potro</name>
		<image>rsz_plazapotro</image>
		<latitude>37.8810301</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.774492</longitude>
		<zoom>17</zoom>
		<description>    The Plaza del Potro is a public square in the Spanish city of Córdoba.

    Rectangular in shape, one end of the plaza has a fountain topped by the figure of a colt with its front legs raised holding a sign with the coat of arms of the city. This Renaissance-style fountain dates from 1577, and the colt which gives its name to the square was added a century later. Until 1847 was located on the opposite side of the plaza.

    Since 1924, the other end of the square has a monument dedicated to the Triumph of the archangel Raphael.

    Among the buildings overlooking the square is the famous Posada del Potro, mentioned by Cervantes in Don Quixote, in addition to the city's Museum of Fine Arts and the Museum Julio Romero de Torres.

    The reference in Don Quixote can be found in the Penguin Classics edition, translated by John D. Rutherford, in Chapter III as " ... Potro in Cordova ...", and in the Barnes &amp; Noble edition, translated by Tobias Smollett, in Chapter III as " ... the spout of Cordoba ...". The much celebrated reference to the place and neighbourhood is made by an inn keeper making fun of Don Quixote with sarcastic chivalrous references to infamous brothels, disreputable districts and dens of iniquity.
		</description>
	</attraction>
    <attraction>
        <name>Roman temple of Córdoba</name>
        <image>romantemple</image>
        <latitude>37.884737</latitude>
        <longitude>-4.776406</longitude>
        <zoom>17</zoom>
        <description>
    The Spanish city of Córdoba has the remains of a Roman temple, which was discovered in the 1950s during the expansion of City Hall. It is located in the angle formed by the streets Claudio Marcelo and Capitulares. It was not the only temple that the city had, but it was possibly the most important of all, and the only known by archaeological excavation. It is a Pseudoperipterus, hexastyle and of Corinthian order temple of 32 meters long and 16 wide.

    Its construction began during the reign of Emperor Claudius (41-54 AD) and ended some forty years later, during the reign of Emperor Domitian (81-96 CE). Presumably it was dedicated to the imperial cult. The temple underwent some changes in the 2nd century, reforms that coincide with the relocation of the colonial forum.

    In the area had already been found architectural elements, such as drums of columns, capitals, etc. all in marble, so the area was known as los marmolejos. This area of Córdoba could become between the 1st century and the 2nd century, as the provincial forum of the Colonia Patricia, title that received the city during the Roman rule.
        </description>
    </attraction>
	<attraction>
		<name>Córdoba</name>
		<image>rsz_portada</image>
		<latitude>37.8788829</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.779565</longitude>
		<zoom>15</zoom>
		<description>    Córdoba, also called Cordova  in English, is a city in Andalusia, southern Spain, and the capital of the province of Córdoba. The old town contains numerous architectural reminders of when Corduba was the capital of Hispania Ulterior during the Roman Republic and capital of Hispania Baetica during the Roman Empire. It was conquered by invading Islamic armies in the eighth century. Qurṭubah  then became the capital of the Islamic Emirate and then Caliphate of Córdoba, including most of the Iberian Peninsula.

    It has been estimated that in the 10th century Córdoba was the most populous city in the world, and under the rule of Caliph Al Hakam II it had also become a centre for education under its Islamic rulers. Al Hakam II opened many libraries on top of the many medical schools and universities which existed at this time. During these centuries Córdoba became a predominantly Muslim society with minorities living in a restricted second-class status. Today it is a moderately sized modern city; its population in 2011 was about 330,000. The historic centre was named a UNESCO World Heritage Site.
		</description>
	</attraction>
	<attraction>
		<name>Puente romano</name>
		<image>puenteromano</image>
		<latitude>37.877165</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.778547</longitude>
		<zoom>17</zoom>
		<description>    The Roman bridge of Córdoba is a bridge in the Historic centre of Córdoba,, built in the early 1st century BC across the Guadalquivir river.

    It is included in the small preserved area known as Sotos de la Albolafia.

    The bridge was built by the Romans in the early 1st century BC, perhaps replacing a previous one in wood. It currently, after the Islamic reconstruction, has 16 arcades, one less than original ones, and a total length of 247 meters. The width is around 9 meters.

    The Via Augusta, which connected Rome to Cádiz, most likely passed through it. During the early Islamic domination the Muslim governor Al-Samh ibn Malik al-Khawlani ordered a bridge to be built on the ruins of what was left of the old Roman construction. In the Middle Ages, the Calahorra Tower and the Puerta del Puente were built at the bridge's southern and northern ends, respectively (the latter is now a 16th-century reconstruction). The bridge was reconstructed and expanded to its current size. The arches depict the famous Moorish architecture that dominates the city's scenery. In the 17th century, a sculpture depicting St. Raphael was put in the mid of the bridge, executed by Bernabé Gómez del Río.

    During its history, the bridge was restored and renovated several times (in particular in the 10th century), and now only the 14th and 15th arches (counting from the Puerta del Puente) are original. It was extensively restored in 2006.
		</description>
	</attraction>
	<attraction>
		<name>Medina Azahara</name>
		<image>rsz_medina</image>
		<latitude>37.8944</latitude>
		<longitude>-4.8386</longitude>
		<zoom>17</zoom>
		<description>    Medina Azahara (Arabic: مدينة الزهراء‎ Madīnat az-Zahrā: literal meaning "the shining city") is the ruins of a vast, fortified Arab Muslim medieval palace-city built by Abd-ar-Rahman III al-Nasir, (912–961) Umayyad Caliph of Córdoba, and located on the western outskirts of Córdoba. It was an Arab Muslim medieval town and the de facto capital of al-Andalus, or Muslim Spain, as the heart of the administration and government was within its walls. Built beginning in 936-940, the city included ceremonial reception halls, mosques, administrative and government offices, gardens, a mint, workshops, barracks, residences, and baths. Water was supplied through aqueducts.

    The main reason for its construction was politico-ideological: the dignity of the Caliph required the establishment of a new city, a symbol of his power, imitating other Eastern Caliphates. Above all, it demonstrated his superiority over his great rivals, the Fatimids of Ifriqiya in Northern Africa.Legend also says it was built as a tribute to the favourite of the Caliph: Azahara.

    The complex was extended during the reign of Abd ar-Rahman III's son Al-Hakam II (r. 961-976), but after his death soon ceased to be the main residence of the Caliphs. In 1010 it was sacked in a civil war, and thereafter abandoned, with many elements re-used elsewhere. Its ruins were excavated starting from the 1910s. Only about 10 percent of the 112 hectares have been excavated and restored, but this area includes the central area, with "two caliphal residences, with associated bath complexes, two aristocratic residences, and service quarters ... spaces associated with the palace guard; some large administrative buildings ... the extraordinary court complex presided over by the reception hall ... the great garden spaces, and just outside this area, the congregational mosque".

    A new museum on the edge of the site has been built low, with much of the space underground, to minimize disruption to the views of the landscape from the ruins, which are also beginning to be affected by modern housing.
		</description>
	</attraction>
    <attraction>
        <name>Torre de la Malmuerta</name>
        <image>torredelamalmuerta</image>
        <latitude>37.8916964</latitude>
        <longitude>-4.777641</longitude>
        <zoom>17</zoom>
        <description>    The Torre de la Malmuerta is a gate tower in Córdoba, Spain.

    This albarrana tower was built in 1406-1408, by order of King Henry III of Castile, over a pre-existing Almohad structure, to defend the gates of Rincón and Colodro. Later it was also used as a prison for nobles.

    Having an octagonal plan, the tower has an annexed arch.

    The names, meaning "Tower of the Bad Dead Woman", refers to a woman who, according to a legend, was killed here by her husband after a false accusation of adultery.</description>
    </attraction>
    <attraction>
        <name>Torre de la Calahorra</name>
        <image>torredelacalahorra</image>
        <latitude>37.875851</latitude>
        <longitude>-4.7765941</longitude>
        <zoom>17</zoom>
        <description>    The Calahorra Tower (Spanish: Torre de la Calahorra) is a fortified gate in the Historic centre of Córdoba, Spain, of Islamic origin.

    The tower was built during the late 12th century by the Almohads to protect the nearby Roman Bridge on the Guadalquivir. The tower, standing on the left bank of the river, originally consisted of an arched gate between two square towers.

    The building was restored in 1369 by king Henry II of Castile. A third tower was added to the existing ones, in the shape of two cylinder connecting them.

    The tower was declared a national historical monument in 1931.

    The restoration of the tower, along with the Roman Bridge, Gate of the Bridge and surrounding area, was awarded the European Union Prize for Cultural Heritage / Europa Nostra Award in 2014</description>
    </attraction>
    <attraction>
        <name>Sinagoga de Córdoba</name>
        <image>sinagogadecordoba</image>
        <latitude>37.879647</latitude>
        <longitude>-4.78334</longitude>
        <zoom>17</zoom>
        <description>    Córdoba Synagogue (Spanish: Sinagoga de Córdoba) is a historic edifice in the Jewish Quarter of Córdoba, Spain built in 1315.

    The synagogue was built in Mudéjar style by architects led by Isaac Moheb. It consists of a courtyard, accessed from the street, which leads to a hallway, followed by the prayer room. On the eastern side of the hall is a staircase that leads to the women's gallery. The gallery overlooks the prayer room through three decorative arches. The prayer room measures 6.95 x 6.37 m.

    After the expulsion of the Jews from Spain in 1492, the building was devoted to various functions including a Hydrophobic hospital, a chapel for shoemakers and nursery school. It was declared a National Monument in 1885. Since then it has undergone several phases of the restoration including that of Felix Hernandez in 1929 and one started in 1977 for the reopening of the building in 1985 to celebrate the 850th anniversary of birth of Maimonides.

    Other well-preserved, pre-expulsion synagogues can be found in Híjar, Toledo, and Tomar.</description>
    </attraction>
</attractions>